(504) 920-3283

i.am.dave.harris@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Over 24 years of experience in business process analysis and information systems integration in direct support of Navy pay and personnel systems administration at both field and corporate levels. A proven record of increasing accuracy and efficiency through technology insertion. An experienced business systems analyst and navy pay and personnel program manager with exceptional organizational, administrative and technical skills.

EXPERIENCE / QUALIFICATION

- Accomplished business and technology professional with vast experience in Navy human resource systems and navy pay and personnel policy and administration.
- Conducted requirements gathering, decomposition and refinement for Navy Standard Integrated Personnel System (NSIPS) implemented under PeopleSoft HRMS 9.01 and Oracle 11g.
- Determined requirements to establish multiple interfaces including flat files and web services.
- Excellent business writing skills; produced functional requirements documents, system requirements specifications, report specifications, requirements traceability matrices, interface control documents, process flow charts, story boards, job performance aids and business rules.
- Sound knowledge and experience with use case reviews, fit-gap analysis, functional design and business process re-engineering.
- Familiar with industry standard design methodologies including agile (Scrum and Rational Unified Process) as well as sequential (waterfall model).
- Proficient with all phases of the Software Development Life Cycle for systems maintenance as well as all major engineering events for new system development and implementation.
- Exceptional written and verbal communication skills.
- Conducted live product demonstrations with stakeholders, application field testers and end users.
- Advanced MS Office user, proficient in Access, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, SharePoint, Visio and Outlook. Performed data extraction translation and load (ETL) by creating complex macros and queries, utilizing functions, formulas and expressions to create and format outputs including, reports, pivot tables, charts and graphs.
- Adept user of PeopleSoft, Serena Dimensions, HP Quality Center, SAP Business Objects, Benthic Golden and Toad for Oracle.
- Experienced with Relational Database Management Systems including basic application of SQL.
- Participated in application unit testing and system testing.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Consultant, NSIPS, Paradyme Management Inc.

August 2014 - Present

Space and Naval Warfare System Center, Atlantic, New Orleans, LA

Functional Lead for Retirements and Separations Task Order. Responsible for a team of four analysts in the accomplishment of requirements gathering and decomposition. Facilitated collaboration between Oracle functional consulting team and the Navy Personnel Command's Better Business Transformation Office. Provided technical and functional support to the government project manager including contract deliverables required to support major engineering events critical to the project life cycle.

Senior Business Systems Analyst, NSIPS, Lockheed Martin

2010 - 2014

Space and Naval Warfare System Center, Atlantic, New Orleans, LA

Concurrently drove multiple work streams as the functional lead for the development of three major subsystems implemented as business process initiatives for enhancement of the Navy Standard Integrated Personnel System (NSIPS) including a financial management system for obligations and expenditures

DAVID J. HARRIS

Active Duty Navy Employment (1990 – 2010)

related to worldwide personnel distribution and assignment. Also worked on maintenance for existing components of the core product and its subsystems. Supported the Navy Program Management Office with all major engineering events including; preliminary design review, critical design review, application system testing, application field testing and production readiness review. Collaborated and coordinated efforts between analysts, developers and testers ensuring project milestones were met and government and contractor project managers were informed of project status. Trained three junior analysts to perform requirements decomposition and documentation. Assisted the Requirements Manager with training, resume reviews, panel interviews and Rough Orders of Magnitude.

Reserve Operations Support, Manpower and Budget Analyst Commander, U.S. Pacific Fleet, Pearl Harbor, HI

2006 - 2010

Defined business solution and developed the implementation plan for incorporating reserve personnel and job assignment data into the combatant commander's Collaboration at Sea (CAS) system. Developed an ETL process to export data from the reserve headquarters legacy system and upload into the CAS system. Also utilized multiple Navy human resource and budget systems to mine data and conduct analysis critical to resource management. Produced and presented executive summary briefs to a panel of flag officers and Senior Executive Service (SES) personnel. Developed and managed \$20 million annual reserve personnel budget. Provided cost benefit analysis and variance models crucial to optimal utilization of resources. Directly supervised one person and provided remote oversight of 14 field activity budget managers.

Military Manpower and Personnel Department Director

2003 - 2006

Navy Operational Support Center, San Diego, CA

Directed personnel distribution and assignments for over 2,800 reserve personnel assigned to 103 units in Southern California at the Navy's largest reserve activity. Managed a staff of nine personnel clerks and supervisors in reserve pay and personnel programs administration conducted using PeopleSoft NSIPS. Performed NSIPS Access Manager (NAM) functions and reviewed and approved workflow items related to multiple facets of reserve pay and personnel transactions. Developed a MS Access database application to generate personnel assignment orders utilizing data imported from a legacy system.

Personnel Officer 2001 - 2003

USS AVENGER, Ingleside, TX

Served as Personnel Officer and Navigation and Administration Department Leading Chief Petty Officer. Supervised eight personnel including administrative, medical and navigation staff. Used PeopleSoft NISPS to manage pay, personnel and benefits for a diverse crew. Also served as Educational Services Officer and Career Information Programs Advisor. Maintained ships personnel qualification database.

Reserve Pay and Personnel Program Manager

1998 - 2001

Navy Reserve Center, Saint Petersburg, FL

Provided Reserve Pay and Personnel Administration using PeopleSoft NSIPS. Transitioned the legacy Reserve Standard Training, Administration and Readiness Support (RSTARS) system to PeopleSoft NSIPS client server version. Ensured all reserve pay and personnel data successfully migrated from the legacy system to NSIPS. Developed a MS Access database application to track advancement exam eligibility requirements, inventory control of navy wide examinations and produce outputs including multiple reports.

Previous work experience also includes: Business Process Reengineering Analyst for Navy Reserve Personnel Center, New Orleans, LA; and Military Personnel Clerk for Personnel Support Detachment, Naval Air Station, New Orleans, LA and USS MEYERKORD.

DAVID J. HARRIS

EDUCATION

- Bachelors of Science, Liberal Arts, Excelsior College, December 2013, (3.77 GPA) with depths in Communications and Administrative Management
- Associates in Applied Sciences, Administrative Management, Excelsior College, March 2009
- Navy Career Information Program Advisor (Navy Counselor), Norfolk, VA, 4 weeks
- Navy Basic Instructor and Curriculum Development, San Diego, CA, 3 weeks
- Equal Employment Opportunity Manger, Pearl Harbor, HI, 1 week
- Navy Personnelman Class "A" School (Navy Occupational Specialty), Meridian, MS, 6 weeks
- Microsoft Access, Excel, Word and PowerPoint levels 1 3, New Horizons, Tampa, FL